<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Artworks on Juan-Pablo Villegas</title>
    <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/artwork/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Artworks on Juan-Pablo Villegas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 04:40:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.jpvd.xyz/artwork/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ocres</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2019/ocres/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 04:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2019/ocres/</guid>
      <description>Ocre consiste en un tríptico de fotografías realizadas en el sendero de los Ocres en Rousillon, Francia y una paleta de acuarelas hecha con pigmentos naturales extraídos de una mina en el mismo lugar. La pieza aborda la relación lingüística entre objeto y concepto a través del juego de palabras que designan al mismo tiempo un lugar, un material y una gama de colores. La relación tautológica entre los colores del paisaje y los materiales con los que se podría llevar a cabo la representación es otro de los puntos de interés del proyecto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>canal</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/canal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/canal/</guid>
      <description>CANAL is a record and a book that researches the sound and visual forms that direct experiences controlled by an emitter. The intention of the project is to frame reality as something that can be built for particular purposes.
Some of the tracks contained in the record are :
Effect / Affect :
Research supports the theory that when different frequencies are presented to each ear through stereo headphones, a new tone (or binaural beat) is created as the brain puts the original tones together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moneda</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/moneda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/moneda/</guid>
      <description>I acquired an archive of 8 mm films and 35 mm slides consisting of images of archaeological pre-hispanic ruins and colonial buildings from various places in Mexico. I worked to extract the silver using different chemical processes. As the original images disappeared, I documented the residue. With the extracted silver, I did a mirror.
  The video installation Moneda consists of three videos displayed under a glass floor through which you can see the vestiges of the Ex Convent of San Jeronimo; a silver mirror mounted on a carousel that revolves around the gallery and a publication printed with movable types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>la purga</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/la-purga/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/la-purga/</guid>
      <description>The Purge was the title of the research project that took place at the Museo de Arte Moderno (MAM) in Mexico City. I investigated the theme of the the uncanny as a will to unravel aspects of architecture, archive, bureaucracy and interaction with the public space. La Purga questioned how subjectivity appropriates a place under strict control as a museum.
Restos (Remains)
Remains left after a performance with a person practicing witchcraft in the surroundings of the exhibition space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>al interior</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/al-interior/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/al-interior/</guid>
      <description>Al Interior it is an exhibition for the interior space of a micro SD card. The four projects reflect on the physical condition of memory and the technical and cultural paradoxes that exist in storage devices.
1. Retícula (Grid)
By progressively cutting the Micro SD memory card, the current trend for greater data storage capacity in a smaller space is questioned. The image signals a grid on fire as an anticipated vision of its obsolescence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fe</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/fe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/fe/</guid>
      <description>Fe -the chemical symbol for iron from the Latin ferratum, but also the Spanish word for faith- proposes a twisted act of belief. Metal has no organic life, however we assume that what we see and hear relates to a familiar realm. Unaware of the magnetic field that provokes the iron to move and thus generate sound, we project life into an inanimate object that appears to crawl, to squeal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nemotecnia</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/nemotecnia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/nemotecnia/</guid>
      <description>Through a luminous impact an afterimage is imprinted in the retina of the spectator. The image consists of a yantra, a graphic machine to induce hallucinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>opaco</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/opaco/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/opaco/</guid>
      <description>Opaco consists in the assembly of audios taken from different suspense films, science fiction and horror. The encounter with otherness is considered as something that puts at risk the limits of our physical and mental identity.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>presencia</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/presencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/presencia/</guid>
      <description>Presencia is a project in which I explore the body as an object and its formal transformations in time and space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sonámbulo</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/son%C3%A1mbulo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/son%C3%A1mbulo/</guid>
      <description>Sleepwalker is an action that translates the fixed image of a painting to film, the soundtrack compose by music, effects, voice, direct sound and subtitles is produced live. The intention is to show the expansive dimension of sound to break with the aesthetic of the two-dimensional image.
  Diseño Sonoro : Luis Ortega
Foley Artist : Bas Tokoro
Sonido Directo : Felix Blum
Voz : Rodrigo Ambriz
Música : Fernando Vigueras</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stanby</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/stanby/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/stanby/</guid>
      <description>Sound piece in which a Shepard Tone was reproduced in the moments between acts during a concert.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>strobe</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/strobe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/strobe/</guid>
      <description>Strobe is an audio-visual performance consisting of one stroboscopic light connected to a sequencer. The intention is to cause psycho-physical effects in response to repetition and rhythmic patterns of sound and light. One of the psychosomatic consequences implicated is the apparition of phantasmagorical images in the viewer&amp;rsquo;s mind.
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>subsuelo</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/subsuelo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/subsuelo/</guid>
      <description>The series of photographs in Subsuelo consists of images altered by the recording of the vibration of an earthquake. As the earthquake intensifies, the distortion of the image increases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tele</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/tele/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/tele/</guid>
      <description>Tele is a sound piece that broadcasts an improvisation that has just taken place in another part of the world through a messaging application. The intention is to think about the dislocation of experiences from geographical and physical distance.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ventana</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/ventana/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/ventana/</guid>
      <description>Ventana is a project in which the limits of man’s perception are questioned, a translucent camera oscura was produced, it filters the ranges that affect the daguerrotype plate to allow us to see its interior while the image is being produced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fuente</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/fuente/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 22:40:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2018/fuente/</guid>
      <description>Fuente investigates animism through material interaction.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>velas</title>
      <link>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2016/velas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 03:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.jpvd.xyz/2016/velas/</guid>
      <description>La fotografía es un reflejo y su memoria radica en la posibilidad del sujeto de mirarse a sí mismo, los espejos entonces son las primeras fotografías, son el primer éxito de una imagen trasladada. La serie Velas consiste en tres espejos de plata realizados sobre vidrios de colores, los espejos funcionan como fotografías utilizando la plata como material sobre el cual nos miramos.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>